The beach that makes you old
Old is a thriller, mystery, horror film directed by M. Night Shyamalan.
A group of families on a tropical holiday discover that the secluded beach where they are staying is
somehow causing them to age rapidly – reducing their entire lives into a single day.
Guy, played by Gael García Bernal.
Prisca, played by Vicky Krieps.
Charles, played by Rufus Sewell.
Trent Aged 15, played by Alex Wolff.
Maddox Aged 16, played by Thomasin McKenzie.
Chrystal, played by Abbey Lee.
Old is a 2021 American mystery thriller film
written, directed, and produced by M.
Night Shyamalan.
It is based on the French-language Swiss graphic novel
Sandcastle by Pierre Oscar Lévy and Frederik Peeters.
The film features an ensemble cast consisting of Gael García Bernal, Vicky Krieps, Rufus Sewell, Alex Wolff, Thomasin
McKenzie, Abbey Lee, Nikki Amuka-Bird, Ken Leung, Eliza Scanlen, Aaron Pierre, Embeth Davidtz, and Emun Elliott.
The plot follows a group of people who find
themselves rapidly aging on a secluded beach.
Shyamalan decided to adapt Sandcastle into a film after
receiving it as a Father's Day gift in 2017.
The untitled project was announced in September 2019, with the
filmmaker revealing a partnership with Universal Pictures.
Filming took place for three months in the Dominican Republic in 2020, during the first
year of the COVID-19 pandemic, with cinematographer Michael Gioulakis.
Old premiered at Jazz at Lincoln Center in New York City on July 19, 2021,
and was theatrically released in the United States on July 23.
The film grossed $90 million worldwide against an $18 million
budget and received mixed reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of beach, husband wife
relationship, schizophrenia, escape, time warp.
The tone is dark and mind_bending and intense.